egnyte.com 2017-08-06

# Egnyte - Privacy Policy

Thank you for visiting Egnyte, Inc.’s website located at www.egnyte.com. Egnyte, Inc. (hereinafter “Egnyte”, “We”, “Us” or “Our”) is concerned about personal privacy and is committed to protecting the privacy of visitors to our website. This Privacy Policy identifies the personally identifiable information that Egnyte collects about you at our website and describes how Egnyte uses and protects such information. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personally identifiable information and how you can access and update this information. The use of information collected through our service shall be limited to the purpose of providing the service for which the Client has engaged Egnyte, Inc.

Egnyte, Inc. participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU–U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. Egnyte, Inc. is committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s <https://www.privacyshield.gov/list>.

Egnyte, Inc. is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. Egnyte, Inc. complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, Egnyte, Inc. is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, Egnyte, Inc. may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.–based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the <https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome>, you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

YOUR USE OF THE WEBSITE OR THE SERVICES OFFERED BY EGNYTE ON THE WEBSITE IS CONDITIONED UPON YOUR ACCEPTANCE OF THE TERMS OF SERVICE LOCATED AT www.egnyte.com AS WELL AS THIS PRIVACY POLICY. IF YOU DO NOT ACCEPT THE TERMS OF SERVICE OR TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY, DO NOT USE THE WEBSITE OR SERVICES OFFERED BY EGNYTE.

## What Information Is Collected

You may visit our website and learn about Egnyte's service offered on the website anonymously.

We collect personally identifiable information about you only if you voluntarily provide it to us when you use an online registration form to create an account for use of the Egnyte service, to submit a reseller inquiry or request additional information about our services. You are required to pick a password and username, and to provide your first name, last name, phone number and email address. We may also ask you, but you are not required to provide, information regarding how you learned about Egnyte.

Egnyte, Inc. collects information under the direction of its Clients, and has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. Egnyte, Inc. works with its Clients to help them provide notice to their customers concerning, the purpose for which personal information is collected.

We collect information for our clients, if you are a customer of one of our Clients and would no longer like to be contacted by one of our Clients that use our service, please contact the client that you interact with directly. If you are a Client and would like to update your account please contact us here http://www.egnyte.com/corp/contact_egnyte.html.

If you purchase a product or service from us, we request certain personally identifiable information from you on our order form. You must provide contact information (such as name and email) and financial information (such as credit card number, expiration date). We use this information for billing purposes and to fill your orders. If we have trouble processing an order, we will use this information to contact you.

When you download and use our mobile application “Egnyte”, we automatically collect information on the type of device you use, system and performance information, and operating system version. We also collect personal information through the mobile app, such as name, telephone number, email address and IP Address. Sensitive personal information is also collected through the mobile app such as credit card information. The application will also request access to allow the use of your device's camera to allow the app to use the camera sensor to take pictures and videos and also access to your photo storage to allow to read, modify or delete access to protected storage. We do not ask you for, access or track any location based information from your mobile device at any time while downloading or using our mobile app or services.

## Use of Information

We use your contact information and unique identifier (such as a user name and password) to provide access to the Egnyte service available on our website and to contact you when reasonably necessary. We may also use any information you have provided as reasonably necessary to administer or provide customer support for the website and the Egnyte service. We use the information submitted by you to send you correspondence and other information that may interest you and to respond to your correspondence. If, for any reason, you would like to be removed from our email list, you can send us an email at [inquiry@egnyte.com](mailto:inquiry@egnyte.com) or follow the unsubscribe information contained in each of the emails you receive.

Based upon the personally identifiable information you provide us, we will send you a welcoming email to verify your username and password. We will also communicate with you in response to your inquiries, to provide the services you request, to manage your account, and to help us improve our customer support and service to you overall. We will communicate with you by email or telephone, in accordance with your wishes. We will send you strictly service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email. Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you have the option to deactivate your account. If you wish to subscribe to our monthly newsletter, we will use your name and email address to send the newsletter to you. Our newsletters contain important information such as updates and enhancements to our services. Out of respect for your privacy, we provide you a way to unsubscribe through the unsubscribe instructions contained in the emails you receive or by contacting us at [inquiry@egnyte.com](mailto:inquiry@egnyte.com). 

We send you push notifications from time-to-time in order to update you about any events or promotions that we may be running. If you no longer wish to receive these types of communications, you may turn them off at the device level. To ensure you receive proper notifications, we will need to collect certain information about your device such as operating system and user identification information.

Finally, if you use the Egnyte service, we will store the data you upload onto our servers. All your data is encrypted at rest. Egnyte may access your account, to respond to service or technical problems or as stated in this Agreement. You, as a Power User with administrator capabilities, may manage the Address Book that includes inputting other Power Users' and Standard Users' first names, last names, and email addresses. You, as a regular Power User, may manage the Address Book that includes inputting Standard Users' first names, last names, and email addresses. Email communications resulting from the management of the Address Book is limited to the initial setup of Power User and Standard User accounts. You, not Egnyte, shall have sole responsibility for the accuracy, quality, integrity, legality, reliability, appropriateness and copyright of all data stored in your account. Furthermore, Egnyte shall not be responsible or liable for the deletion, correction, destruction, damage, loss or failure to store any data.

## Disclosure of Information

We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy statement. We may disclose your personally identifiable information to certain third party vendors (e.g., data storage facilities, payment processors, email service providers) used by Egnyte to assist us in providing the Egnyte services, to the extent necessary to enable such vendors to provide such assistance. These third parties are prohibited from using your personally identifiable information for any other purposes. If you do not want us to share your personal information with these companies, contact us here http://www.egnyte.com/corp/contact_egnyte.html.

  1. We may send email offers to selected groups of Egnyte users on behalf of our company and on behalf of other businesses in whose products and services you may have an interest; but we will not disclose any of your personally identifiable information to any such businesses. We will also include in each such email instructions as to how you can permanently opt-out of receiving any such future emails. In addition you may contact us at [inquiry@egnyte.com](mailto:inquiry@egnyte.com) to request that your information no longer be used. 
  2. In certain situations, Egnyte, Inc. may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. We also reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information if we reasonably believe we are required to do so by law, regulation or other government authority and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our website. 
  3. Finally, we may disclose your personally identifiable information upon a transfer or sale to another entity of all or substantially all of Egnyte's assets or stock in Egnyte's line of business to which this privacy policy relates or upon any other corporate reorganization. (If, for example, in the future, we undergo any sort of corporate reorganization, we may need to transfer your personally identifiable information to the surviving entity.) You will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website of any change in ownership or uses of your personally identifiable information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personally identifiable information. 

## Updating Your Information

Egnyte, Inc. has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. An individual who seeks access, who seeks to correct, amend, delete inaccurate data or withdraw consent to further contact should direct his/her query to Egnyte, Inc.‘s Client (the data controller). If the Client requests Egnyte, Inc. to remove the data, we will respond to their request within 30 days.

Upon request Egnyte, Inc. will provide you with information about whether we hold, or process on behalf of a third party, any of your personal information. To update any of your personally identifiable information previously submitted to Egnyte you may do so within the Account Settings section of your account when logged in. If you would like to access your personally identifiable information in order to correct, update, or delete it, you may also contact us directly at [inquiry@egnyte.com](mailto:inquiry@egnyte.com). Requests for access will be responded to within a reasonable timeframe.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. Egnyte, Inc. will retain personal data we process on behalf of our Clients for as long as needed to provide services to our Client. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

## Blog/Testimonials

If you use a blog or testimonial on this site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. For testimonials, we do obtain the customer's consent prior to posting their name and photograph along with their testimonial. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums. If you want to remove your personally identifiable information that is being displayed on our website under public pages, please contact us at [inquiry@egnyte.com](mailto:inquiry@egnyte.com). 

A Special Note about Children

Our website does not gather any personally identifiable information from children that we know are under the age of 13. We believe strongly that parents should play an integral part in their child's on-line experience and should monitor that activity to ensure on-line sites are respecting their child's privacy. For additional information on protecting children's privacy, visit [ https://www.consumer.ftc.gov/blog/kids-online-privacy-next-generation](https://www.consumer.ftc.gov/blog/kids-online-privacy-next-generation).

## Log Files

As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, User Agent type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.

We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users' movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We do not link this automatically-collected data to personally identifiable information.

We use third-party tracking services that use cookies to track non-personally identifiable information about visitors to our site in the aggregate. Information tracked includes the search engine used by a visitor, keyword input by a visitor, and search campaign associated with a visitor. The information is captured for marketing and customer segmentation purposes.

## Cookies and other Tracking Technologies

Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by Egnyte and our partners, affiliates, or analytics or service providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the website, tracking users' movements around the website and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

We use cookies for our shopping cart, to remember users' settings (e.g. language preference), for authentication. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our website, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited.

## Local Storage Objects (HTML5)

We use Local Storage Objects (LSOs) such as HTML5 to store content information and preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our website or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity use LSOs such as HTML 5. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs.

## Behavioral Targeting / Re-Targeting

We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our website or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this website and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) (or if located in the European Union click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads. 

## Mobile Analytics

We use mobile analytics software to allow us to better understand the functionality of our Mobile Software on your phone. This software may record information such as how often you use the application, the events that occur within the application, aggregated usage, performance data, and where the application was downloaded from. We do not link the information we store within the analytics software to any personally identifiable information you submit within the mobile application.

## Links to Third Party Websites

We may place from time to time links on our website to one or more websites for our affiliates. Some affiliates may collect personally identifiable information when you access their links or when you indicate you would like to participate in a special offer. When you click on a link to a third party website from our website, your activity and use on the linked website is governed by that website's policies, not by those of Egnyte. We encourage you to visit their websites and review their privacy and user policies. This privacy policy applies only to information collected by this website.

## Security Measures

The security of your personally identifiable information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as credit card number) on our registration or order forms, we use reasonable security to encrypt that data and send it securely. We offer you two step verification when you access your account. Our website employs procedural and technological measures, consistent with legal requirements and the demands of customer service, reasonably designed to protect your personally identifiable information and your data from loss, misuse or unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction, including using secure servers for data storage. We restrict access to personally identifiable information to only a subset of Egnyte employees.

We follow generally accepted standards and best practices to protect the personally identifiable information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact us at [inquiry@egnyte.com](mailto:inquiry@egnyte.com). 

## Social Media Features and Widgets

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

## Information Related to Data Collected through the Egnyte Service

Information Related to Data Collected for our Clients

  * Egnyte collects information under the direction of its Clients, and has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personally identifiable information it processes. If you are a customer of one of our Clients and would no longer like to be contacted by one of our Clients that use our service, please contact the Client that you interact with directly. We may transfer personally identifiable information to companies that help us provide our service. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the service agreements with our Clients. 
  * We use sub-processors in order to [send emails on behalf of our clients] 

Access and Retention of Data Controlled by our Clients:

  * Egnyte has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personally identifiable information it processes. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data should direct his query to the Egnyte's Client (the data controller). If requested to remove data we will respond within a reasonable timeframe. 
  * We will retain personally identifiable information we process on behalf of our Clients for as long as needed to provide services to our Client. Egnyte will retain this personally identifiable information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

## Policy Changes

Due to the Internet's rapidly evolving nature, Egnyte may need to update this Privacy Policy from time to time. If so, Egnyte will post its updated policy on this system. We reserve the right to modify this privacy policy at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page prior to change becoming effective.

## Questions

If you have any questions related to this Privacy Policy please contact us at:   
Egnyte, Inc.   
Attn: Kris Lahiri   
1350 W. Middlefield Road   
Mountain View, CA 94043   

Last Updated 09/16/2016

## Egnyte Information

Egnyte HIPAA Statement [PDF]   
HIPAA Business Associate Agreement [PDF]
